<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<data>
    <meta>
        <source>
            <p>Source: <a href="http://www.wikipedia.org">Wikipedia.org</a></p>
        </source>
    </meta>
    <page href="/" title="Home">
        <div class="abstract">
            <p><strong>Ajax</strong> (also known as <strong>AJAX</strong>), shorthand for "<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asynchrony" title="Asynchrony">Asynchronous</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JavaScript" title="JavaScript">JavaScript</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XML" title="XML">XML</a>", is a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_development" title="Web development">development</a> technique for creating interactive <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_application" title="Web application">web applications</a>. The intent is to make web pages feel more responsive by exchanging small amounts of data with the server behind the scenes, so that the entire web page does not have to be reloaded each time the user requests a change. This is intended to increase the web page's interactivity, speed, and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usability" title="Usability">usability</a>.</p>
        </div>
    </page>
    <page href="/history" title="History">
        <div class="abstract">
            <p>The first use of the term in public was by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_James_Garrett" title="Jesse James Garrett">Jesse James Garrett</a> in February 2005. Garrett thought of the term when he realized the need for a shorthand term to represent the suite of technologies he was proposing to a client.</p>
            <p>Although the term <em>Ajax</em> was coined in 2005, most of the technologies that enable Ajax started a decade earlier with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft" title="Microsoft">Microsoft</a>'s initiatives in developing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Remote_Scripting" title="Remote Scripting">Remote Scripting</a>. Techniques for the asynchronous loading of content on an existing Web page without requiring a full reload date back as far as the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IFrame" title="IFrame">IFRAME</a> element type (introduced in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Explorer" title="Internet Explorer">Internet Explorer</a> 3 in 1996) and the LAYER element type (introduced in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Netscape" title="Netscape">Netscape</a> 4 in 1997, abandoned during early development of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mozilla" title="Mozilla">Mozilla</a>). Both element types had a <code>src</code> attribute that could take any external <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Locator" title="Uniform Resource Locator">URL</a>, and by loading a page containing JavaScript that manipulated the parent page, Ajax-like effects could be attained. This set of client-side technologies was usually grouped together under the generic term of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DHTML" title="DHTML">DHTML</a>. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macromedia" title="Macromedia">Macromedia</a>'s Flash could also, from version 4, load <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XML" title="XML">XML</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comma-separated_values" title="Comma-separated values">CSV</a> files from a remote server without requiring a browser being refreshed.</p>
        </div>
    </page>
    <page href="/technologies" title="Technologies">
        <div class="abstract">
            <p>The Ajax technique uses a combination of:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XHTML" title="XHTML">XHTML</a> (or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML" title="HTML">HTML</a>) and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cascading_Style_Sheets" title="Cascading Style Sheets">CSS</a>, for marking up and styling information.</li>
                <li>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document_Object_Model" title="Document Object Model">DOM</a> accessed with a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Client-side" title="Client-side">client-side</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scripting_language" title="Scripting language">scripting language</a>, especially <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ECMAScript" title="ECMAScript">ECMAScript</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Implementation" title="Implementation">implementations</a> such as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JavaScript" title="JavaScript">JavaScript</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JScript" title="JScript">JScript</a>, to dynamically display and interact with the information presented.</li>
                <li>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XMLHttpRequest" title="XMLHttpRequest">XMLHttpRequest</a> object is used to exchange data asynchronously with the web server. In some <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ajax_framework" title="Ajax framework">Ajax frameworks</a> and in certain situations, an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IFrame" title="IFrame">IFrame</a> object is used instead of the XMLHttpRequest object to exchange data with the web server, and in other implementations, dynamically added &lt;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Client-side_JavaScript" title="Client-side JavaScript">script</a>&gt; tags may be used.</li>
                <li>XML is sometimes used as the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File_format" title="File format">format</a> for transferring data between the server and client, although any format will work, including preformatted HTML, plain text, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JavaScript_Object_Notation" title="JavaScript Object Notation">JSON</a> and even <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extensible_Binary_Meta_Language" title="Extensible Binary Meta Language">EBML</a>. These files may be created dynamically by some form of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Server-side_scripting" title="Server-side scripting">server-side scripting</a>.</li>
            </ul>
        </div>
    </page>
    <page href="/justification" title="Justification">
        <div class="abstract">
            <p>The core justification for Ajax style programming is to overcome the page loading requirements of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML" title="HTML">HTML</a>/<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP" title="HTTP">HTTP</a>-mediated web pages. Ajax creates the necessary initial conditions for the evolution of complex, intuitive, dynamic, data-centric user interfaces in web pages-the realization of that goal is still a work in progress.</p>
            <p>Web pages, unlike native applications, are <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loose_coupling" title="Loose coupling">loosely coupled</a>, meaning that the data they display are not tightly bound to data sources and must be first <i>marshalled</i> (set out in proper order) into an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML" title="HTML">HTML</a> page format before they can be presented to a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_agent" title="User agent">user agent</a> on the client machine. For this reason, web pages have to be re-loaded each time a user needs to view different datasets. By using the XMLHttpRequest object to request and return data without a re-load, a programmer by-passes this requirement and makes the loosely coupled web page behave much like a tightly coupled application, but with a more variable lag time for the data to pass through a longer "wire" to the remote web browser.</p>
        </div>
    </page>
</data>